<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Code Quality on QAware | Software Engineering Blog</title><link>https://qaware.github.io/tags/code-quality/</link><description>Recent content in Code Quality on QAware | Software Engineering Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © 2020, QAware GmbH; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 15:06:32 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://qaware.github.io/tags/code-quality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>MaLTeSQuE / SANER 2018</title><link>https://qaware.github.io/posts/2018-05-09-maltesque-saner/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 15:06:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://qaware.github.io/posts/2018-05-09-maltesque-saner/</guid><description>The 25th conference on Software Analysis, Evaluation and Reengineering (SANER) and its co-located workshops took place in the Italian city of Campobasso on March 20-23, 2018. Due to its remoteness, and train and flight delays, it wasn’t easy to reach, but the hospitability and the amazing food made well up for that.
Day 0 (workshop day) The first day after the long journey started with different workshops. I participated in the workshop on machine learning techniques for software quality evaluation (MaLTeSQuE), presenting an industrial evaluation of machine learning (ML) approaches for run-time anomaly detection.</description></item><item><title>"I know it when I see it": Perceptions of Code Quality (Part 2)</title><link>https://qaware.github.io/posts/2017-12-20-i-know-it-when-i-see-it-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 15:06:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://qaware.github.io/posts/2017-12-20-i-know-it-when-i-see-it-2/</guid><description>Background In Part 1 of this article, I have described the motivation and scope of a research project into the perceptions of code quality by different stakeholders. The project has been conducted by a consortium which two scientists from Sweden and I led. The first set of results from that project has been accepted for publication in the ITiCSE’17 proceedings recently1, and that is what I report on in this article.</description></item></channel></rss>